# **Rachel Dooley**

**Tel.** 480-307-2175 | Chattanooga, TN **Email:** <u>rachelandersondooley@gmail.com</u> **Portfolio:** https://rachelandersondooley.com **GitHub:** https://github.com/rae1821

### **Summary**

Solution oriented frontend developer experienced in HTML5/CSS3,JavaScript, APIs, React + experience using Git repositories. Highly skilled at delivering world class customer service with excellent communication skills while building custom solutions using common web frameworks such as TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, and WordPress. Dedicated to writing organized, well-documented code and interested in working on projects in a team environment while continuing to learn and grow my skills as a developer.

## **Experience**

## Freelance & Coding Bootcamp | Skillcrush + Scrimba

2022 - present

- HTML/CSS experience designed and coded 10+ fully responsive web-based applications
- JS/React utilized JavaScript & React to add interactivity to fully responsive sites
- Experience working with APIs adept at utilizing information obtained through API
- Earned frontend developer certification from Skillcrush bootcamp
- Currently completing frontend developer certification from Scrimba bootcamp

# Stay At Home Parent | Hixson, TN

2016-2022

- Assumed all primary caregiver and household duties with excellent organization and time management
- Utilized naptime to make and sell custom garments on Etsy & started coding journey

#### IT Manager | Ophthalmologist Office

2015-2016

- Developed fully responsive custom website with HTML/CSS/JavaScript using SEO best practices resulting in 25% increase in new patients in one year
- Provided technical support and used troubleshooting and debugging software to fix any issues

## **Student Services Manager** | University of Phoenix

2008-2014

- Motivated a team of 12 using strengths first approach to foster growth resulting in a 25% increase in engagement in 3 years.
- Designed leadership program for academic counselors resulting in 2 management promotions in 6 months while working in a team environment.
- Spearheaded departmental initiatives and increased customer satisfaction from 30% to 70% in 6 months
- Devised creative strategies to achieve quarterly departmental and organizational goals while managing vision and purpose

#### **Education**

- Master of Science in Psychology University of Phoenix
- Bachelor of Arts in History University of Tennessee